What's up preppies?
Hello everyone.
Welcome back to our journey of conquering our IELTS writing skills today.
I'm sure many of you here have participated in a debate at
least once, whether it's at school, at work or in everyday life.
That's when you express your opinion and if you want your opponent
or listeners to find it reasonable, you need to provide more persuasive
reasons to support it.
The question type we'll learn in today's lesson is also similar to
that.
You need to convince readers that your arguments are completely reasonable.
This question type is called Agree or Disagree.
Our lesson is divided into three parts.
1.
Analyse Agree and Disagree questions and brainstorm ideas using the listing
technique.
2.
Introduce sample outlines and essays.
3.
Analyse sample essays and improve task response to band 6 to achieve
three goals.
1.
Understand how to analyse Agree and Disagree questions.
2.
Use listing technique to brainstorm ideas for Agree and Disagree questions.
3.
Understand how to make an outline for an Agree or Disagree essay
at band 6.
So now, let's get started.
As we learned in the previous lesson, the first step after reading
the question is task analysis to find out three components.
Let's review this part through an exercise.
You have 30 seconds to underline and identify the three components of
the following question.
Let's start by analysing the question to ensure we stay on track.
First, we identify the topic words.
These tell us the general subject.
In this sentence, schools should teach children.
The topic here is clearly schools and their responsibility.
Next, we look for the microtopic words.
These narrow down the specific areas we must discuss.
Here, we have two distinct responsibilities being compared.
1.
Teach children how to behave well.
Good behaviour.
2.
Teach them school subjects.
Formal academic education.
Therefore, all the ideas in your body paragraphs must focus on these
two specific aspects.
Finally, the instruction words.
These tell us what to do with the topic.
The question asks, to what extent do you agree or disagree?
So, this is an Agree, Disagree question.
To meet the requirements of this type, you need to show that
you agree or disagree with the topic.
Besides providing formal education, whether schools have a responsibility to
teach students good behaviours or not.
With the Agree or Disagree questions, I'd like to introduce three approaches.
and disagree with the rest.
For the given question, I'm going to show you three opinions.
Please match them with the corresponding approaches.
If you choose Disagree in two body paragraphs, you will only give
the reasons why schools are not responsible for teaching children good
behaviours in addition to providing formal education.
If you choose Partly, in two body paragraphs, you have to do
two tasks.
Identify who shares this responsibility and explain why schools also have part
of the responsibility for educating children on good behaviour.
If you choose Agree, in two body paragraphs, you will only give
the reasons why schools are responsible for teaching children good behaviours
in addition to providing formal education.
Alright, you've understood what to do in each approach, haven't you?
No matter which approach you take, you still need to have ideas
to write.
Now we have a technique for brainstorming ideas.
It's called listing.
In this technique, we list all the ideas related to the topic,
then select and organise ideas in the writing.
Alright, let's practice this technique.
If you disagree, try to use English to list them out.
Behaviours lead to positive relationships among children and a safe and
supporting learning environment.
Parents are closer to their children.
They provide moral guidance more effectively.
Heavy curriculum leads to no time for behaviour education.
Large class sizes make it difficult for teachers to tailor to each
child's character.
With the list of ideas above, please identify which ideas could be
used for the Totally Agree essay, meaning that schools are responsible for
teaching children good behaviours, and which ideas could be used for the
Totally Disagree essay, schools are not responsible for teaching children good
behaviours.
Please organise the ideas into the table below.
You can pause the video for about 1-2 minutes to do
this task.
Have you all finished?
Now, please look at the table you've just organised, and I'll introduce
two ways of writing.
Support only one side, agree or disagree, and write about both sides,
but choose one side to support more.
However, here's some advice for you.
It's better to avoid supporting only one side, because it's harder for
you to write.
It requires more ideas and can be less convincing, which might result
in getting lower scores from the examiner.
For example, with the suggested list of ideas, I can organise them
as, for Agree, children spending most of their day at school.
Busier parents lead to school's heavy influence.
Students treat each other nicely, not bullying.
Better future ahead, career, dealing with differences and ideas with respect.
Lessons on behaviours lead to positive relationships among children and a safe
and supporting learning environment.
Disagree.
Parents are closer to their children, which means they provide moral guidance
more effectively.
Heavy curriculum leads to no time for behaviour education.
Large class sizes make it difficult for teachers to tailor to each
child's characters.
Write about both sides, but support Agree more.
We can see that because there are more ideas about the Agree,
we need to write about both sides, but support the side of
Agree more.
So, have you understood three approaches for Agree or Disagree essays clearly?
This video is quite long already.
We'll continue in the next video.
See you!